shawcable.net 2012-05-19

# Shaw Privacy Policy — The principles, definitions and commitment to your privacy - Shaw.ca

##  Privacy Policy 

_Privacy Policy last revised on Nov. 12,  2008_

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, please email us or use the contact information  
shown on any of Shaw's websites.

  1. ## 1\. Our commitment to you

Shaw’s core business is providing broadband cable television, Internet services and digital phone services and such other products and services that Shaw may provide from time to time. Shaw has always been and will continue to be committed to protecting Personal Information. Shaw has established its Privacy Policy using the ten principles set out in the National Standard of Canada entitled Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information. These ten principles are the following:

    1. Being accountable 
    2. Identifying the purposes for Personal Information collection 
    3. Obtaining consent 
    4. Limiting the collection of Personal Information 
    5. Limiting the use, disclosure and retention of Personal Information 
    6. Keeping Personal Information accurate 
    7. Safeguarding Personal Information 
    8. Being open about policies and practises 
    9. Providing access to Personal Information 
    10. Listening to our customers’ feedback and suggestions 

Shaw relies on these ten principles to protect the Personal Information collected from its’ Customers, Employees and Web Site Users. Shaw has established its Privacy Policy in accordance with _The Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act._

  2. ## 2\. Definitions

Shaw: 
    Shaw Cablesystems G.P. includes its partners and associates, as they may exist from time to time. 

Customer: 
    Any individual who has an account with Shaw and/or uses, has used, or applies to use Shaw’s products and/or services. 

Employee: 
    Any individual who works for, or provides labour to Shaw or one of its subsidiary companies in exchange for wages or salary. 

Personal Information: 
    Information about an identifiable individual, but does not include the name, title or business address or telephone number of an employee of an organization. 

Web Site User: 
    User of a Web site controlled by Shaw from which we collect Personal Information.

  3. ## 3\. Frequently asked questions

    * **3.1 What type of Personal Information does Shaw collect?**

3.1.1 The Personal Information most often collected and maintained in your Customer file may include (but is not limited to) name, address for service, mailing address, phone number(s), a piece of acceptable identification, alternate contact information, banking information for payment, non-Shaw email address, if you are an eBill user and requests for service and enquiries. 

3.1.2 The Personal Information most often collected and maintained in your Employee file may include (but is not limited to) name, address, phone number(s), emergency contact information, date of birth, Social Insurance number, banking information, past employment information, earnings information, performance reviews/letters, dependant and beneficiary information.

3.1.3 The Personal Information most often collected in relation with Web Site Users may include (but is not limited to) name, phone number, email address.

    * **3.2 Why does Shaw collect Personal Information?**

3.2.1 Shaw collects Customer’s Personal Information for the following purposes, to:

      1. establish and maintain a responsible commercial relationship with you; 
      2. understand your needs as a Customer and your eligibility for products and services; 
      3. recommend particular products, services and opportunities to its Customers; 
      4. develop, enhance and market products and service and/or provide products and services to its Customers; 
      5. process billing and collection of the fees for the Shaw products and services you have purchased and/or subscribed to; 
      6. perform credit checks, if deemed necessary by Shaw; 
      7. deliver its products and/or services to its Customers; and 
      8. meet Shaw’s legal and regulatory requirements. 

3.2.2 Shaw collects Employee’s Personal Information for the following purposes, to: 

      1. administer payroll and benefits; 
      2. administer personnel and employment programs; 
      3. document an Employee’s file in the normal course of the employment relationship (i.e. performance reviews, etc.); and 
      4. provide references regarding current or former employees in response to requests from prospective employers

3.2.3 Shaw collects Web Site User’s Personal Information for purposes generally identified at the time of collection. These purposes may include to:

      1. send you information, updates you’ve requested, or answer your questions 
      2. register your participation to a contest 
      3. register you in an encrypted secure zone 
      4. assess your job application

Use of Cookies: During a Customer’s interaction with one of Shaw’s Internet sites, Shaw may use a browser feature called a “cookie” to collect information anonymously and track user patterns on Shaw’s Web sites. A cookie is a small text file containing a unique identification number that identifies a Customer’s browser – but not the Customer him or herself – to Shaw’s computers each time a Customer visits one of the Shaw Web sites using cookies. Cookies tell Shaw which pages of its sites are visited and how many people visited each web page. This helps Shaw to enhance the on-line experience of visitors to the Shaw Web sites. Cookies also serve to identify your computer so that your preferences can be saved for future visits.

When Shaw chooses to use Personal Information for a purpose not previously identified, Shaw will identify the new use. Unless such new use is required by law, the Consent of the Customer, Employee or Web Site User is required before the Personal Information can be used for that new purpose. 

    * **3.3 How does Shaw obtain your consent?**

Consent is required for the collection of Personal Information and the subsequent use or disclosure of the Personal Information. Consent can be either expressed or implied. The form of consent sought by Shaw may vary, depending upon the circumstances and the type of Personal Information. In determining the form of consent to use, Shaw takes into account the sensitivity of the information and the reasonable expectations of the Customer, Employee or Web Site User. Shaw generally seeks express consent when the Personal Information is likely to be considered sensitive. Implied consent is typically appropriate when the Personal Information is less sensitive.

In exceptional circumstances, as permitted by law, Shaw may collect, use or disclose Personal Information without a Customer, Employee or Web Site User’s knowledge or consent.

In general, the use of products and services by a Customer, or a Web Site User, or the acceptance of employment or benefits by an Employee, will constitute implied consent required by Shaw to collect, use and/or disclose Personal Information for the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy. 

Consent may be withdrawn by Customers and Web Site Users at any time, subject to legal or contractual restrictions and upon providing Shaw reasonable notice. If you wish to withdraw your consent to certain collection, use or disclosure of Personal Information, please contact Shaw at [privacy@shaw.ca](mailto:privacy@shaw.ca).

    * **3.4 When and how does Shaw disclose Personal Information?**

Internally, only Shaw’s employees with a business need to know, or whose duties reasonably so require, are granted access to Personal Information of Shaw’s Customers and employees.

3.4.1 Shaw may disclose Customer’s Personal Information to:

      1. a company who will be involved in supplying the Customer with communications or communications directory-related products and/or services; 
      2. a company or individual if disclosure is for the development, enhancement, promotion, marketing or provision of any of Shaw’s current products and/or services or for any new products and/or services of Shaw subject to confidentiality requirements; 
      3. in conjunction with special offers or programs to program partners, or third party agents responsible for administering such offers or programs. Any such disclosure is made on a confidential basis; 
      4. an agent used by Shaw to evaluate the Customer’s credit worthiness or to collect the Customer’s account; 
      5. a credit reporting agency; and 
      6. a third party or parties, where the Customer has given Shaw Consent to such disclosure or if disclosure is required by law, in accordance with _The Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_. 

3.4.2 Shaw may disclose Personal Information about its Employees to:

      1. a third party or parties for payroll and benefits administration; 
      2. a third party or parties to administer personnel and employment programs 
      3. a person or a company in the context of providing references regarding current or former employees in response to requests from prospective employers; and 
      4. a third party or parties, where the Employee has given Shaw consent to such disclosure or if disclosure is required by law, particularly in accordance with _The Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_. 

3.4.3 Shaw may disclose Personal Information about Web Site Users to:

      1. a third party or parties, where the Web Site User has given Shaw consent to such disclosure or if disclosure is required by law, in accordance with _The Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_. 

    * **3.5 Who does Shaw share Personal Information with?**

Shaw does not sell Personal Information about its Customers, Employees and/or Web Site Users. Shaw may share a Customer’s Personal Information with its partners, associates and third party service providers in order to fulfill the purposes identified in Subsection 3.1. In such cases, the relationship with the partner, associate or third party is governed by strict confidentiality standards and policies to ensure the Customer’s information is secure and treated in accordance with _The Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act_ and with the utmost care and respect.

    * **3.6 How does Shaw safeguard your Personal Information?**

The nature of the safeguards will vary depending on the sensitivity of the Personal Information that has been Collected, the scope of the information, and the method of storage of that information. More sensitive types of Personal Information will be safeguarded by a higher level of protection.

    * **3.7 How do I access Shaw’s policies and procedures?**

Shaw will make readily available to Customers, Employees and Web Site Users specific information about its policies and procedures relating to the management of Personal Information.

Shaw will be open about its policies and procedures with respect to the management of Personal Information. Customers, Employees and Web Site Users will be able to enquire about Shaw’s privacy policies and procedures at minimal cost and without unreasonable efforts on their part. This information is available to Customers and Web Site users by writing to Shaw, to the attention of the Privacy Officer at 630-3rd Ave S.W., Calgary, AB, T2P 4L4, and to Employees by writing to the attention of the HR Department at 630-3rd Ave S.W., Calgary, AB, T2P 4L4.

    * **3.8 How do I access my Personal Information?**

You may access and verify your Personal Information held by Shaw by submitting a request in writing to Shaw’s Privacy Officer at 630-3rd Ave S.W., Calgary, AB, T2P 4L4. A response will be mailed to the address on your account or file.

Shaw will respond to a Customer, Employee or Web Site User’s request within a reasonable period of time and at minimal or no cost. 

In certain circumstances, Shaw may not be able to provide access to all the Personal Information it holds, for example, when the disclosure would reveal confidential business information, if the Personal Information is protected by solicitor-client privilege, if the Personal Information was collected during an inquiry into a breach of contract or violation of a federal or provincial law.

    * **3.9 How can I challenge compliance and offer suggestions?**

A Customer or employee of Shaw may direct any questions or inquires with respect to the privacy principles outlined above or about Shaw’s practices described in its’ Privacy Policy to [privacy@shaw.ca](mailto:privacy@shaw.ca) or to Shaw’s Privacy Officer at 630-3rd Ave S.W., Calgary, AB, T2P 4L4.

Shaw will investigate all complaints and respond to all questions asked by its Customers and/or employees. If a complaint is found to be justified, Shaw will take appropriate measures to resolve the complaint, which may include amending its policies and procedures if necessary.

If Customers are not satisfied with Shaw’s response to a complaint or inquires about compliant procedures they may contact the office of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada, at:   
Toll-free: 1-800-282-1376  
Phone: (613) 995-8210  
Fax: (613) 947-6850

    * **4 - Your role in protecting your Personal Information:**

Please remember that Shaw’s Privacy Policy and our use of your Personal Information only applies to the information you provide and we caution that if you disclose Personal Information or personally sensitive data through use of the Internet such as through chat rooms, communities, bulletin boards or other public online forums, this information is not collected by or for Shaw but may be collected and used by other persons or companies over which Shaw has no control. It is your responsibility to review the privacy statements of any person or company to whom you choose to link, from or through the use of any Shaw Internet services. Shaw is not responsible for privacy statements or compliance or other content of any Web site not owned or managed by Shaw or Shaw’s group of companies. 

Shaw does its’ best to protect and safeguard Personal Information and we believe there are measures you should take as well. Do not share your Personal Information such as bank card numbers, credit card numbers, associated pin numbers or Social Insurance numbers with others unless you clearly understand the purpose of their request and you know with whom you are dealing. Do not keep sensitive Personal Information in your email inbox or on Webmail. Provide us with one acceptable piece of identification that will be kept in your Customer file, so we can identify you when you call us. If you are asked to assign passwords to connect you to your Personal Information, you should use a combination of letters and numbers and do not use words that can be easily associated with you (example: do not use the name of a family member or pet), we also suggest you change your password regularly. If ever you are suspicious of any telephone, mail or email promotional campaigns or you suspect fraudulent activity, please contact us at [privacy@shaw.ca](mailto:privacy@shaw.ca) to verify that the campaign is a legitimate Shaw activity.

    * **5 - Updating this Privacy Policy**

Any changes to Shaw’s Privacy Policy shall be acknowledged in this Policy in a timely manner. Shaw may modify or remove portions of this Privacy Policy when it feels it is necessary and appropriate. You may determine when this Privacy Policy was last updated by referring to the date found at the top right-hand corner of the first page of this Privacy Policy _"Privacy Policy last revised on:_____"_

Terms and Conditions

* Offer subject to change. Prices shown do not include tax. Shaw Phone and Internet Services are subject to Shaw’s Acceptable Use policies under Terms of Use. Not all Shaw services are available in all regions. Channels and programming vary by region. Equipment not purchased by you must be returned to Shaw if your Shaw Services are cancelled. You may not resell any Shaw Services. Other conditions may apply.

† † If you sign up for the Shaw Easy Own program, you will obtain title to the hardware immediately with the understanding you are required to pay Shaw for the hardware in 36 pre-authorized monthly installments. You also agree any outstanding balance is due immediately to Shaw if Shaw Services are terminated. Additional terms and conditions will apply. For more information, visit our Terms of Use.

© 2012 Shaw Communications Inc. All Rights Reserved.
